War  at its worse fought by young men at their best
Hamburger Hill is a war, action, drama film directed by John Irvin.
The men of Bravo Company are facing a battle
that's all uphill… up Hamburger Hill.
Fourteen war-weary soldiers are battling for a mud-covered mound of earth
so named because it chews up soldiers like chopped meat.
They are fighting for their country, their fellow soldiers and their lives.
War is hell, but this is worse.
Hamburger Hill tells it the way it was, the way it really was.
It's a raw, gritty and totally unrelenting dramatic depiction of one
of the fiercest battles of America's bloodiest war.
This happened.
Hamburger Hill - war at its worst, men at their best.
Sgt. Adam Frantz, played by Dylan McDermott.
Sfc. Dennis Worcester, played by Steven Weber.
Pvt. Joe Beletsky, played by Tim Quill.
Spc Motown, played by Michael Boatman.
Pvt Vincent 'Alphabet' Languilli, played by Anthony Barrile.
Pvt. Washburn, played by Don Cheadle.
Hamburger Hill is a 1987 American war film set during the Battle of Hamburger
Hill, a May 1969 assault during the Vietnam War by the U.S.
Army's 3rd Battalion, 187th Infantry, 101st Airborne Division, on a ridge
of Dong Ap Bia near the Laotian border in central Vietnam.
The ridge was a well-fortified position, including
trenchworks and bunkers, of the North Vietnamese Army.
military records of the battle refer to the mountain as "Hill 937," its map designation
having been derived from the high elevation of the hill at 937 meters (3,074 ft).
Written by James Carabatsos and directed by John Irvin, the film starred Michael
Boatman, Don Cheadle, Dylan McDermott (his film debut), Courtney B.
Vance, Steven Weber, and Tim Quill.
It was produced by RKO Pictures and distributed by Paramount
Pictures, and was shot in the Philippines.
The novelization was written by William Pelfrey.
The film explores themes of vietnam war, insanity, gi, u.s. air force, us army.
The tone is dark and emotional.